Mohammad AlDamiri Senior Electrical Engineer

E-mail address: engaldamiri85@gmail.com

Contact Numbers:

+966565794381 Saudi Arabia / Riyadh.

Nationality: Jordanian. / Visa Status: Valid (Transferable).

12+ years of extensive experience in electrical systems at Mega construction projects (High-rise buildings, Hospital 500 Bed, and Riyadh Metro project) Specialist in executing and managing electrical systems implementation cycle from setting up the material submittal registers to delivery, and implementation to getting TOC. Highly skilled in procurement, estimation, value engineering, technical evaluation, cost reduction, and approving solutions, as well as having extensive sources of suppliers and sub-contractors.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING:

Bachelor of Science in **Electrical Power Engineering**, Al-Balqa Applied University, Faculty of Engineering Technology Jordan - Amman, Jun 2009.

Professional Experience:

1- Conversion MEP Company.

Senior Electrical Engineer from March 2023 - Present.

SAICO tower project.

Duties and Responsibilities:

- o Review the technical submittal of materials and ensure their compliance with projectspecifications.
- o Study all technical drawings, documents, and any revisions thereon and raise technical queries for any conflicting information within the project technical document.
- o Monitoring work progress-planned versus achieved.
- o Provided technical support during construction, start-up, testing, system commissioning, and performance monitoring.
- o Supervising the construction in terms of proper method, material reservation, and optimum output of labor to engage with the planning department to define project activities within the scope of work.
- o Follow up orders and deliveries with suppliers to expedite and avoid any delays.
- Project: KAFD- Parcel 4.07 (4 Basement and 18 Floor) and Parcel 4.08 (4Basement and 30 Floor) Rivadh, Saudi Arabia.

Senior Electrical Engineer from Feb 2020 - March 2023.

Duties and Responsibilities:

 Responsible for testing and commissioning for LV and LC for three parcelsat KAFD (P4.02, P4.07, P4.08) and getting TOC.





- o Prepared installation and testing method statements, Checklists, test plans, and test reports for quality assurance purposes, and proceeded to submit ATP, and CIR.
- Follow up and prepare all site surveys and LC and LV dilapidation reports for legacy activities. Preparedness to complete all activities T&C as per procedure ATP1 to ATP4 and CIR to get TOC certificate.
- Study all technical drawings, documents, and any revisions thereon and raise technical queries for any conflicting information within the project technical document.
- Preparing the material submittal registers to ensure that all materials approvals and procurement activities are properly scheduled and allocated to the appropriate budget items in the Bill of Quantities.
 - Responsible for all Electrical work such as Transformer, RMU, ATS, MCC, MDB, Generator, Bus way, Structure Cabling, cable Tray, Cable Trunking, low voltage systems (lighting system, small power, Emergency light) low current systems such as BMS, CCTV, MATV, Fire alarm system, Nurse call system, Public Adders system, ICT and Non-ICT, Clock Master system, DMS, Mechanical equipment, and TVS (TunnelVentilation System).
- O Supervising the construction in terms of proper method, material reservation, and optimum output of labor to engage with the planning department to define project activities within the scope of work.
- o Issue RFP for Electrical packages to the market, and carry out and lead all technical/commercial negotiations with subcontractors.
- o Provided technical support during construction, start-up, testing, system commissioning, and performance monitoring.
- o Monitoring work progress-planned versus achieved.

2-First Gulf Company (FGC).

Senior Electrical Engineer from April 2019 – Feb 2020

Project: Riyadh Metro Project (line 1).

Duties and Responsibilities:

- Review the technical submittal of materials and ensure their compliance with project specifications.
- o Supervise the preparation of fully detailed shop drawings required to execute the project.
- o Arrangement of tools, equipment, and materials.
- o Providing suitable work instructions to work.
- o Monitoring work progress-planned versus achieved.
- o Follow up orders and deliveries with suppliers to expedite and avoid any delays.
- o Provided technical support during construction, start-up, testing, system commissioning, and performance monitoring.
- o Prepared MR, MIR, and WIR and followed up with the site engineer for installation as per MS.



3- A&P Partner J&P (Overseas) Limited.

Senior Electrical Engineer from Jan 2017 – April 2019



Project: KAP2E, KING ABDULLAH SECURITY PROJECT (Forces Camps, Medical Center Residential Building, Services and Utilities Building, infrastructure working, substation room).

Duties and Responsibilities:

- o Review the technical submittal of materials and ensure its compliance with project specifications.
- o Supervise preparation of full detailed shop drawings required to execute the project.
- o Doing material take-off and raising the purchase requests according to approved shop drawings.
- o Worked directly with the design department in cable and breakers sizing, earthing and lightning protection calculations, short circuit calculations, DB calculations, Fault calculations, and lighting design and calculations to achieve full conformity with the project specifications and scope of work.
- Slashed electrical systems costs by negotiating economic technical solutions and pricing with vendors while ensuring full compliance with project specifications and scope of work.
- o Arrangement of tools, equipment, materials.
- o Providing suitable work instructions to work.
- o Monitoring work progress-planned versus achieved.
- o Follow up orders and deliver with suppliers to expedite and avoid delays.
- o Provided technical support during construction, start-up, testing, system commissioning, and performance monitoring.
- o Prepared MR, MIR, WIR and follow up with site engineer for installation as per MS.
- Participated in preparing shop drawings and electrical calculations.
- Take decisions according to site cases and requirements.

4- AL Fouzan Trading & General Construction Co (FTCO).

From Feb 2010 - Jan 2017.

Position: Project Electrical Engineer from March 2014 to Feb 2017.

Project: (Madinah Hajj City (High-Rise Buildings) Hotels & Infrastructure working.

Consultant office: Dar al Hadassah.

Position: Site Electrical Engineer from April 2012 to March 2014. Project: AL-JOUF UNIVERSITY STAFF HOUSING and two Mosques. Consultant office: TYPSA consulting engineering.

Position: Site Electrical Engineer from Feb 2010 to April 2012. Project: Prince Mohammed bin Abdul Aziz Hospital, 500 Bed.

Duties and Responsibilities:

Senior ELECTRICAL ENGINEER

o Arrangement of tools, equipment, materials.

Mohammad AlDamiri





- o Providing suitable work instructions to work.
- o Monitoring work progress-planned versus achieved.
- Make decisions according to site cases and requirements.
- Review the technical submittal of materials and ensure its compliance with project specifications.
- o Follow up orders and deliveries with suppliers to expedite and avoid any delays.
- o Prepared MR, MIR, WIR and follow up with site engineer for installation as per MS.
- Supervise preparation of full detailed shop drawings required to execute the project.
- Doing material take-off and raising the purchase requests according to approved shop drawings.
- Provided technical support during, start-up, testing, system commissioning, and performance monitoring.

Personal Skills:

- o Languages: Arabic (Mother Language), English (Very Good).
- Computer Skills & Programs: Microsoft office (Excel, Word, PowerPoint), AutoCAD,
 PCM

Memberships:

- o Member of the Jordan Engineers Association.
- Member of Saudi Council of Engineers.

Courses:

- o Design of electrical work in the JEA, Project Cost Estimation &Control.
- Data center physical infrastructure course from Schneider on 3 Aug 2021
- o 3VA molded case circuit breaker course from Siemens.
- Insulation Resistance Testing course from Fluke.
- o Digital Multimeter Basics course from Fluke.
- o 3TM Vacuum contactors course from Siemens.
- o Building Controls course from Schneider.
- Motor and Drive Troubleshooting from Fluke.